# Simu Liu Full Stack Developer

🔀 simuliu711@gmail.com 👂 Manseau, QC, Canada 🌎 apple0441 💲 @pple711

#### **Profile**

Full stack developer with over 8+ years of experience in Java/JS, Angular, Vue, React, Python, Node.js. In improving user engagement by 15%, reducing development and deployment time by 20% and mentoring junior developers, resulting in a 10% improvement in team satisfaction scores. I have also good experience of teamwork

## **Professional Experience**

#### **HubSpot,** Full Stack Developer □

03/2021 - 05/2023 | Remote

HubSpot is a leading inbound marketing and sales software company headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts, USA.

- Founded in 2006 by Brian Halligan and Dharmesh Shah.
- Engineered a membership platform from scratch using MERN; increased retention rate by 5% and saved the company 10 hours of manual work per week
- Researched and created a new application to be used by the company, resulting in a 1.2x increase in sales
- Generated \$500K+in annual ad revenue as a system administrator of a large network of websites.
- Developed a node. is server to validate membership and track digital badges being used, saving the company \$22.5K.
- Mentored 4 team members, enabling them to achieve professional growth and personal goals
- Developed the process of testing and recording the results of the test, thereby increasing the number of tests completed per day by 10%

#### Straight North, Full Stack Developer ☑

01/2019 - 02/2021 | Baltimore, United States

Straight North, headquartered in west-suburban Chicago, IL, is an Internet marketing agency serving middle market companies. Their team of experts makes every click count by creating websites and Internet marketing campaigns that generate sales leads and increase revenue.

- Fostered a culture of collaboration within the team by implementing agile methodologies, leading to a 10% increase in project efficiency and a 5% reduction in time-to-market
- Designing a new web application to enhance collaboration between design, engineering and sales teams increased revenue by 10% in one quarter.
- Built a custom web application for a major client, successfully delivering an integrated CRM system in just 2 weeks
- Developed a new technique for reducing the time it takes to fix crashes by 20%

#### Fareportal, Junior Web Developer ☑

12/2016 – 12/2018 | New York, United States

Fareportal is a leading travel technology company that operates a number of websites which serve customers both online and with telephone.

- Designed and implemented a new cloud-based mobile POS platform, resulting in a 2.5% increase in customer retention
- Coordinated cross-functional teams of hardware and software developers to ensure seamless integration of the new POS system; achieved 10% reduction in transaction processing time
- Continued to develop specialty skills related to his expertise in mobile POS and payment technologies
- Developed and continuously improved an internal knowledge base of best practices for software development

## **Education**

### **Bachelor of Computer Science,**

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology(HKUST) ♂

09/2012 - 11/2016 | Kowloon, Hong Kong

## **Skills**

MERN MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js	••••	<b>MEAN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, Node.js	• • • •
<b>MEVN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, Vue.js, Node.js	••••	<b>Django</b> (HTML, CSS, JS/TS, python)	• • • •
<b>Database</b> MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, NoSQL	••••	<b>Cloud</b> Firebase, Cloudflare, AWS	
Figma	• • • •	Others Python, C/C++, C#/.NET, WordPress, Larav	• • • • • • vel

## Languages

English • • • • Chinese • • • •